Guide to the Swift and Hine Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Swift and Hine Company collection
1834-1890
MS 1408
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
3
(5 boxes)
The collection consists of correspondence, blotters, bills, daybooks, and legal papers of the Smith and Hine Company, a general store in Warren, Connecticut. The material mainly concerns the sale of groceries and dry goods.
Swift and Hine Company
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Whitlock's, 1956. Transferred from the Account Books Collection (MS 29), 1985.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The Swift and Hine Company Collection is composed of account books, receipts and letters documenting the operation of a general store in Warren (Litchfield County), Connecticut, between 1834 and 1874, although a few items date to 1890. The store operated under various names; the earliest ledger is in the name of J. & E. Swift, and blotters from the 1840s and 1850s may represent a partnership of B. Gilbert and Swift. Bills from the 1840s and 1850s are addressed to Swift & Whittlesey; in the 1860s the firm was known as Swift & Hine; and a daybook of the early 1870s is that of Orlando Hine. Bills document purchases from wholesale grocers, druggists, stationers, and clothing, hardware and dry goods merchants, mainly in Hartford; blotters, daybooks, and ledgers record sales to local residents. The records were purchased from Whitlock's in 1956.
Business; General stores; Connecticut -- Commerce; Warren (Conn.); Account books; Bills (financial); Blotters; Daybooks; Businessmen; Hine, Orlando; Swift and Hine Company
- Inventory
  - Bills, 1845 - 1858 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Blotters, 1840 - 1848 (Box 1, Folder 2 - 6)
  - Blotters, 1848-1867 (Box 2, Folder 7 - 12)
  - Daybooks, 1860 - 1862 (Box 3, Folder 13 - 14)
  - Daybooks, 1862 - 1874 (Box 4, Folder 15 - 18)
  - Legal papers, 1849; 1870 - 1871 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Journal, [ca 1840] (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Ledger, 1834 - 1836 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Letters, 1852 - 1890 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Loose papers, 1839 - 1882 (Box 5, Folder 23 - 24)